

PROFESSIONAL STATEMENT

Experienced professional with 3 years of experience analyzing data and improving business processes. Positive and energetic worker with a diverse background and education in technology and data analysis. Strong ability to collect, organize, and interpret data into a reportable format for different business users to understand.

I make it my top priority to see that any position I fulfill is done well and efficiently. Being able to progress, constantly improve, and be agile is always necessary.

AALIYAH LEWIS

Data Analyst

+(757) 754-7870

alewi010@odu.edu

Virginia Beach, VA

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/aaliyahjlewis

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

SQL

Excel & VBA

Problem Solving & Communication

Data Visualization

Leadership

CERTIFICATIONS

Certified Associate in **Project Management** (CAPM)

PMI (Sept 2019 - Sept 2024)

OTHER TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python **SDLC VBA** JAVA **Power Pivot** Html

EXPERIENCE

DATA ANALYST

Patient Advocate Foundation/Hampton, VA/2020 - Current

- Create monthly reports in tableau
- Write stored procedures in SQL to automate business processes 0
- Utilize VBA code to insert data into database
- Create executive level reports/ summaries to utilize for important business processes

FINANCIAL CONTROL ANALYST

ZIM Integrated Shipping LTD./Norfolk, VA/2018 - 2020

- Analyze and review financial statements and sales revenues, costs, expenses, and tariff rates for all business units of leading process automation company
- Develop detailed spreadsheets to identify trends and develop forecasts.
- Consolidate and analyze monthly results and budgets to recover non-manifested expenses.
- Conducted quantitative analysis of financial data to forecast revenue, identify future trends, and assess the risk.
- Developed comprehensive reports, abstracts, and charts for departments to use to better their individual processes.
- Trained employees on reports and programs within the systems.
- Created training manuals on reports.

BUSINESS SYSTEMS ANALYST, INTERN

MDV/Spartan Nash/Norfolk, VA/2017-2018

- Collected data utilizing SQL and offered suggestions on the company's decision support system
- Worked closely with manager to analyze & understand Business requirements; Gathered user functional and non-functional requirements & translated the requirements into User Stories
- Read code to find where changes to the business would affect the system
- Assisted developers with changes and tested business processes
- Created project documents such as scope document, schedule, and budget

EDUCATION

M.S. Data Science & Analytics

Old Dominion University/Norfolk, VA/Current

B.S.B.A Major: Information Systems & Technology

Minor: Business Analytics & Supply Chain Management

Old Dominion University/Norfolk, VA/ 2018